publicis sapient

Associate Software Development Engineer 1

SUMMARY

Daniel Duke is an Associate Software Engineer based out of the Atlanta office. He joined Sapient in July of 2021 as a full time employee after completing two rounds of internships. He is experienced in web development, focused on the XT craft. He has worked on client projects using Javascript, HTML, CSS, Angular, as well as Salesforce LWC and APEX. He also has experience with the Mendix low code platform. His work on client accounts have included developing MVPs, presenting to clients, building out new applications, and maintaining and expanding on existing applications by creating new features, addressing defects, and supporting releases. He also has experience in working with offshore team members, both by facilitating knowledge transfers and in meeting to hand off work and provide better coverage for the client.

Before joining Publicis Sapient, Daniel worked as a commercial painter for several years, where he gained experience in leading small teams and talking directly with clients. He also worked as a tutor during his time in college. Daniel graduated from Georgia Institute of Technology with a Bachelors Degree in Computer Science in 2021.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Publicis Sapient

July 2021 To Present

Marriott, Associate Software Engineer

Description: The Marriott Empower Resapp project is a Lift and Shift effort to rebuild an existing app inside Salesforce using native Salesforce technologies, primarily Lightning Web Components and APEX classes. The project also includes transitioning from a traditional API backend to utilizing the Apollo GraphQL framework.

Roles and Responsibilities: My role on the project was aligned to building out the Foundational Component library, which meant identifying and implementing reusable components that would be in several places across the application. This responsibility required me to think about the application as an overall system, and look for opportunities to use the same component across different pages and user flows, identifying different functional requirements to determine reusability. This also meant getting new requests for an enhancement to a foundational component, and iterating on their functionalities to allow even further use. As the project continued my work slowly shifted toward general delivery, which included working on new features and components, building out pages, integrating the GraphQL queries, and completing API to GraphQL conversion analysis.

Technical Responsibilities:

- Implementing foundational components, with a focus on flexibility and reusability, 5 of which are used in over 120 locations in the application
- Expansion of project Storybook with foundational components and documentation
- Completing detailed UI build out based on provided designs, with a primary focus on accessibility





- Analysis of old application's API queries and conversion of that into the new GraphQL queries
- Writing and integrating GraphQL queries into the new application
- Integration of a URL parameter, which was used to query the salesforce org, and return data needed to launch the application
- Developing POC of FreedomPay integration based on client requirements
- Address defects and bugs across the application

Other responsibilities:

- Guidance and oversight of shadow engineer, who became an integral part of the team
- Meeting with offshore squad members to transfer knowledge and explain features
- Active role in backlog refinement, sprint planning, and other scrum ceremonies
- Demoing sprint work and POC to client
- Answering client's technical questions
- Development of detailed documentation on the URL parameter integration

Skills/Domain: Salesforce Apex, Visual force pages, lightning web components, CSS, html, Javascript

Verizon, Junior Associate Software Engineer

Description: The Verizon business prospect application handles business customers as they purchase cell phones and one-talk devices from the verizon.com/business website. This includes several different user flows, dozens of unique pages, and covers a range from new users browsing devices all the way through the ordering process. This website is visited daily by thousands of users and is a key part of Verizon's business. The onshore XT team was small, with two associate developers and one manager.

As a Junior XT developer working on a small onshore team, had to quickly learn how to work on every aspect of the project and be able to handle issues that came up anywhere in the project. My primary responsibility was to handle urgent client needs and quickly address any issues or defects that came up during US business hours. In between those issues, participated in the usual sprint cycles, completing user stories and fixing defects for upcoming releases.

Technical responsibilities included:

- Addressing defects found by QA and the client
- Implementing features including new navigation methods, page redesigns, alternative payment options, SEO improvements, and improving error handling system
- Refactor code to allow more control of the site via AEM updates

publicis sapient

Associate Software Development Engineer 1

- Developing MVP of a new way to utilize AEM for content organization of the site
- Supporting release by validating the changes that went into production and immediately addressing any defects or bugs that appeared

Other responsibilities:

- Working closely with the offshore team to facilitate hand offs and knowledge shares to ensure the everyone was up to date on current defects and client priorities, as well as best practices and the how to use new tools
- Engage frequently and directly with stakeholders and Verizon employees to discuss stories, defects, and implementation methods
- Creating documentation for the project and all tools used by the front-end team

Skills/Domain: Angular, HTML, CSS, Typescript, AEM, Agile

Publicis Sapient

July 2020 To August 2020

Phillips 66, Software Developer Intern

Description:Develop the MVP for the Phillips 66 Ace app, which is an internal social media site for Phillips 66 employees to share their achievements and collaborate with each other. Features include: posting, sharing, following, profiles, and other common social media features.

Roles and Responsibilities:Worked on a small team of interns to develop multiple features of the MVP using Mendix, and presented the app to Phillips 66 multiple times throughout the internship for feedback and ideation.

Finally, pitched the app to Phillips 66 at the end of the internship and had it accepted by the client, which was taken on as a full project and is still an active project for Publicis Sapient in 2022.

Skills/Domain: Front-end Development, Mendix, Agile

Publicis Sapient

June 2019 To August 2019

Mercedes Benz, Software Developer Intern

Description:Create an interactive app that enables costumers to design a custom Mercedes vehicle while inside the dealership by interacting with a large touch-screen display. It was designed to be light-weight and run from a micro-computer, so performance and efficiency were primary concerns. It also used a CMS via AWS to allow the client to update and change the app based on events or deals without developer intervention.





Roles and Responsibilities:Worked with another intern to develop a proof of concept for packaging the app using electron, as well as updating multiple pages from static designs so that they were able to work with the CMS as it was implemented across the app.

Skills/Domain: Vue, HTML, CSS

Internship Industry Challenge - Alexa App, Software Developer Intern

Description:Following a prompt provided by Publicis Sapient, designed an Alexa app which the user could interact with verbally to get information about their Telco account, as well as make common changes such as parental controls and make payments. Out of the 16 teams across North America, our project won the Best Overall Solution award from a panel of industry leaders at Publicis Sapient.

Work with one other intern developer to design and implement several Alexa functions via AWS Lambda functions.

Connect the Lambda functions to a created database via HTTP requests in Javascript.

Thorough testing of the voice recognition and response systems to ensure a smooth MVP and presentation.

Skills/Domain: AWS, JavaScript, HTTP API

USA Painting

July 2011 To August 2016

Atlanta Motor Speedway, Project Supervisor

Description:A long term contract with Atlanta Motor Speedway to maintain the race track and handle any painting or coating related work needed.

Roles and Responsibilities:Responsible for numerous sites and projects, managing teams of workers in deadline and time sensitive environments.

The primary contact for the client on these sites and worked with them directly to analyze their needs and plan effective solutions.

On longer term projects, oversaw daily and weekly progress and addressed any issues that arose to ensure that the team could stay on schedule and deliver to the client without missing deadline or going over budget.

Skills/Domain: Management, Client interaction, Solution Design and Implementation

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science, (Computer Science): Georgia Institute of Technology, 2021

Associate of Science, (Computer Science): Georgia State University, 2016





SKILLS:

Additional Skill(s): Adobe AEM,XT - Angular,XT-Web: Responsive

Other Skills: Basic knowledge of React framework | Salesforce LWC and APEX

ADDITIONAL DETAILS:

Certification/Trainings

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals -- 2022

Awards

Best Overall Solution - Internship Industry Challenge -- 2019